SWATHI B ACHARYA

Senior Software Engineer

CONTACT

Address

Koramangala, Bangalore, India, 560034

Phone

+91-9481512964

E-mail

swathibachar@amail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sw athi-acharya

SKILLS

Swift, C, C++, Flutter, Objective-C

Tools: Xcode, SourceTree, Crashlytics, Monday, JIRA, GitHub

Application Platforms: iOS

Architectural Pattern: MVVM, MVP, MVC

Version Control Tools: GIT, Subversion

REST API integration

Cocoapods

CI/CD

Creative Senior Software Engineer offering 7+ years of work experience. Skilled in iOS App development with Swift (7 years) and close to 1 year with Flutter. Enthusiastic about developing forward-thinking solutions to tomorrow's productivity problems, both in a team and independently. In previous roles developed 10+ iOS apps.

WORK EXPERIENCE

2021-07 -Current

Senior Software Engineer

Open Financial Technologies, Bangalore, India

- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to design and develop robust solutions to meet requirements for functionality, scalability and performance.
- Managed technological issues for assigned projects, increasing customer satisfaction.
- Migrated old code to modern development standards by reducing waiting time.
- Worked on UI implementation, Firebase, Localization, API integration, JSON parsing and 3rd party SDK integration
- Implemented Asymmetric cryptography and SIM binding.

2016-05 -2021-06

Software Engineer

Robosoft Technologies Pvt. Ltd, Udupi, India

- Implemented iOS standard architecture to build quality apps.
- Collaborated with the quality assurance team to confirm app compatibility.
- Offered friendly and efficient service to clients, managed challenging situations with ease.
- Connected with clients to understand needs and provide excellent service.
- Developed 8+ iOS Apps

PROJECTS

Open Financial Technologies OpenBook

https://apps.apple.com/in/app/openbook-banking-accounting/id1582456899

OpenBook is a one stop solution for every small business owner of India. Now any business owner can manage their banking & business finance from just one app. This is the best app if business is run by traditional means such as ledgers, khata, manual entry books etc.

LANGUAGES KNOWN

English (Fluent)

German (Basic / A1 level (Certified))

Hindi (Fluent)

Kannada (Fluent)

Tulu (Native)

Axis Bank (Hybrid app)

https://apps.apple.com/in/app/neo-for-business/id6449532092

This App was developed for Axis Bank which is a hybrid app with native screens and web pages.

Responsibilities: Involved in the screen implementation. Login, SIM binding, Asymmetric encryption & decryption

Robosoft Technologies

- **PayPay:** PayPay is a Japanese based mobile app. It has a pay function using barcode or QRCode.
- NADL: https://apps.apple.com/in/app/nadlaccountaggregator/id1471066990

An Account Aggregator app from NADL. The company has been set up by leading banks and public institutions and is incorporated as a union government company.

• Voot kids (TvOS):

https://apps.apple.com/in/app/vootINTERESTS kids/id1035290695#?platform=appleTV

This is a TV application for kids. There are E-Books, audio & video stories, games across different skill domains for a complete entertainment & learning experience for kids.

 I12wrk(KASSARA DMCC): https://apps.apple.com/in/app/i12wrk /id1320833147

The new job searching mobile app is here! All the capabilities are created to improve your job hunt.

• **HealthMindr(**Softura):

This is a study based mobile app, to increase pre-exposure prophylaxis (PrEP), MSM, HIV.

Paytm(One97 Communications):
 https://apps.apple.com/in/app/paytmpayments-

bank-account/id473941634

Paytm is India's largest leading payment gateway that offers comprehensive payment services for customer and merchants.

EDUCATION

2012-05 -2016-05

Bachelor of Engineering (B.E): Computer Science and Engineering

N.M.A.M Institute of Technology - Nitte, Karkala (India)

INTERESTS

Sports (Volleyball, Throwball), Cooking, Reading Novels